merrell.com 2019-08-07

# Merrell Privacy Policy

## PRIVACY POLICY

**Last Updated: August 2, 2019**   
Merrell, a division of Wolverine World Wide, Inc., referred to collectively with its affiliated entities and portfolio of brands, as “Wolverine,” “we,” “us,” or “our”, collects information about you when you take advantage of our online services or visit or interact with any of our websites, including www.merrell.com (the “Site”). This privacy policy (the “Policy”) describes: (1) the types of information we may collect about you, and your use of the Site; (2) how we may use and share that information; and (3) the choices you may make with respect to your personal information.

**BY USING THIS SITE, YOU AGREE TO BE BOUND BY THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH ANY OF THE TERMS OF THE PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT USE THIS SITE OR PROVIDE US WITH YOUR INFORMATION.**

**_Personal Information We Collect_**   
_Information You Give Us._ You provide us with your personal information when you use this Site or otherwise communicate with us, including when you:

  * Purchase products on the Site;
  * Create or update an account on the Site;
  * Subscribe to e-mail newsletters or updates;
  * Submit product reviews;
  * Complete, submit, or otherwise participate in surveys or questionnaires; or
  * Participate in contests, sweepstakes, and other promotions.

We collect personal information you choose to provide, which may include your name, email address, gender, date of birth, billing and shipping addresses, telephone number, geolocation data, and/or credit card information. We may retain your responses to surveys and questionnaires that you may complete from time to time. We may collect other information from you that is not specifically listed here. We may use such information in accordance with this Policy. Please do not submit information that you do not want us to have. 

_Information Automatically Collected._ Our servers and third party service providers may automatically record certain information about how you use the Site, such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address, device and browser type, operating system, DNS, the pages or features of the Site that you browsed and the time spent on those pages or features, the frequency with which you use the Site, the links that you click on or use, and other statistics. We collect this information in server logs and by using cookies and similar tracking technologies. See more about our use of cookies below.

_Information We Get From Others._ We may obtain additional information about you from third party sources, such as service providers, vendors, social media sites, and advertising agencies to provide you with more relevant information about our services.

**_How We May Use Your Personal Information_**   
_To Improve the Site and Communicate with You._ We generally use your personal information to serve you, to improve our products, services, and other offerings, and to improve your consumer experience. For example, we use personal information to provide products and services to you, communicate with you about those products and services, and enhance your experience on the Site. Specifically, your personal information may be used to process transactions, respond to questions, maintain online accounts, send you information about products or services that may be of interest to you, analyze and monitor visitor activity on the Site, provide product recommendations and reviews, publish the results of contests, sweepstakes, or other promotions, comply with our legal obligations, and develop a knowledge base regarding users of the Site, including through data analytics.

_In Combination With Other Information._ In addition, we may combine your personal information with, or match your personal information to, information that we receive from other sources, including from third party business partners. For example, we may use third party information to confirm contact information or to better understand your interests by associating demographic information with the information you have provided.

_To Send You Marketing Communications._ We may use the personal information that you provide us to send you communications inviting you to participate in various programs, like surveys or focus groups. We may also send you promotional communications and other offerings to thank you for your feedback or participation in programs, or to share new product launches or sales events. You may opt out of receiving them as described in the Your Choices section below.

_To Improve our Site and Services._ We may use statistical information about visitors to our Site to gain a better understanding of the users of our Site, to improve our Site, and to improve our services. We reserve the right to license or sell aggregate, de-identified information about the visitors to our Site, but this information will not contain your personal information or otherwise be individually identifiable.

_For Compliance, Fraud Prevention and Safety._ We may use your personal information as we believe appropriate to (a) investigate or prevent violation of the law or your agreements with us; (b) protect our, your or others’ rights, privacy, safety or property (including by prosecuting and defending legal claims); (c) protect, investigate and deter against fraudulent, harmful, unauthorized, unethical or illegal activity; (d) comply with applicable laws, lawful requests and legal process, such as to respond to subpoenas or requests from government authorities; and (e) where permitted by law in connection with a legal investigation. For example, we may share information with law enforcement to reduce the risk of fraud or if someone uses or attempts to use our Site for illegal reasons.

**_How We May Share Your Personal Information_**   
We may share your personal information with others for a number of different reasons. We may share your personal information to fulfill your requests, to provide you with information regarding products and services of ours or those of others, to comply with law, and to enforce our rights. We also may share personal information among our affiliated companies, businesses, licensees, distributors, any of our brands, and with our successors and assigns. 

Examples of how we may share your personal information include:

> _With Service Providers, Business Partners, and Vendors:_ We may use third parties to help us design and operate the Site, provide services to support the Site, process your information, and provide marketing activities on our behalf. For example, if you purchase goods through our Site, we will have to provide credit card information to our credit card processor for payment purposes. We will also have to provide your name and address to the company that ships our merchandise. Similarly, we may share personal information with designers, manufacturers, distributors, licensees, marketing and advertising partners, and parties that provide services for the Site in accordance with this Policy. We also may retain other companies and individuals to perform services on our behalf, and we may collaborate with other companies and individuals with respect to particular products or services (collectively, “Providers”). Examples of Providers include data analysis firms, credit card processing companies, customer service and support providers, email and SMS vendors, web hosting and development companies, and fulfillment companies. Providers also include our co-promotion partners for products that we jointly develop and/or market with other companies. Some Providers also may collect information on our behalf from our Site. These third parties may be provided with access to personal information needed to perform their functions.
> 
> _To Comply with Law or to Protect Our Rights:_ We may disclose your personal information as required by law, when we believe disclosure is necessary to comply with a regulatory requirement, judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on us, or to protect the safety, rights, or property of our customers, the public, or Wolverine.
> 
> _To Members of the Corporate Family:_ Wolverine may disclose your personal information to our brands, subsidiaries and affiliates, and their agents and employees.
> 
> _In Connection with Business Transfers:_ If we license, sell, or transfer a company business unit (such as a product line or one or more affiliated companies) to a third party, or enter into discussions regarding such a transaction, we may share your personal information with that party in accordance with this Policy.

**_Cookies and Other Tools That May Collect Information About You_**   
In addition to personal information you may provide directly to us, Wolverine and its business partners may collect and store information about you and your use of the Site through cookies, tracking pixels, and other technologies (collectively, the “Tools”). Cookies are small text files that are stored by your browser on your computer’s hard drive.

We collect, use, and modify this information to better understand, customize, and improve your experience with the Site and other websites, services, and offerings, as well as to manage our advertising. For example, we use web analytics services that leverage these Tools to help us understand how visitors engage with and navigate our Site, e.g., how and when pages on the Site are visited and by how many visitors. We are also able to offer our visitors a more customized and relevant experience on the Site by delivering, through the use of these Tools, content and functionality based on your preferences and interests. If you have provided us with personal information, e.g., through a registration or a request for certain materials, we may associate that personal information with information gathered through the Tools. This allows us to offer increased personalization and functionality.

We may from time to time contract with third-party vendors to work on our behalf to provide ads to our customers via the Internet or to send direct mail or catalogs to customers whom we think may be interested in our products or services. In order to do so, these third parties may collect information concerning visitors to the Site using JavaScript software code and other Tools. Our vendors may then connect the information that they collect from our Site using these Tools to other sources of information, which may include your name and mailing address, for the purpose of sending you direct mail promotions. 

To learn more about the use of cookies generally or other technologies to deliver more relevant advertising, and to better understand how to manage your personal information, including access to and use by certain service providers, please visit [http://www.aboutads.info/choices.](http://www.aboutads.info/choices)

If you do not wish for cookies to be placed on your computer, most web browsers permit you to prevent that from taking place. Information about opting out of cookie-based advertising can be found via the following links: [http://optout.networkadvertising.org](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) and [https://www.neustar.biz/privacy/opt-out.](https://www.neustar.biz/privacy/opt-out) Please keep in mind that cookies and similar technologies are an important part of how the Site works, and removing, rejecting, or limiting the use of these tools might affect the availability and functionality of our Site.

**_Do Not Track Disclosures_**   
Do Not Track (“DNT”) is a privacy preference that users can set in their web browsers. When a user turns on DNT, the browser sends a message to websites requesting that they do not track the user. At this time, we ignore these signals. We do not change our practices, described elsewhere in this Policy, in response to DNT browser settings or signals. In particular, even if you have turned on DNT, we and others will continue to collect information about you and your activity through the use of cookies, tracking pixels, and other Tools. For information about DNT, visit [www.allaboutdnt.org.](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/)

**_Your Choices_**

 _Opting Out of Communications and Updating Your Preferences._

To access, update or modify your personal information, choose not to receive marketing or other promotional communications from us, including direct mail or catalogues, or otherwise change your choices about how we use your personal information, please: (1) update your account details online; (2) follow the unsubscribe instructions located at the end of any marketing communication from us; (3) contact us using the contact information provided at the end of this Policy. Please be sure to include in any email or postal mail your full name, email address, postal address, and any message. Please note that such requests may take up to thirty (30) days to become effective.

Please contact us if you have any questions or concerns about your personal information or require assistance in managing your choices.

_Consequences of Not Providing Personal Information._  
You are not required to provide all personal information identified in this Policy to use our Site or to interact with us offline, but certain functionality will not be available if you do not provide personal information. For example, if you do not provide personal information, we may not be able to respond to your request, perform a transaction with you, or provide you with marketing that we believe you would find valuable.

**_Security_**   
No security program is impenetrable, and criminals have proven adept at circumventing widely adopted security safeguards, so we cannot always guarantee the security of personal information. There are inherent risks in shopping online.

Any user or third party accessing our Site or services is responsible for its own use of the Site and the services. We are not responsible for any third party’s actions or its security controls with respect to information that third parties may collect or process via the website, services, or otherwise.

_Be Aware of “Phishing.”_ “Phishing” is a scam designed to steal your personal information. If you receive an email that looks like it is us asking you for your personal information, do not reply to it. **We will not request your password, user name, credit card information, or other personal information through email.**

**_Other Websites_**   
The Site may contain links to websites of third parties that: (1) are not affiliated with us; (2) are outside our control; or (3) are not covered by this Policy, including without limitation sites operated by our distributors and/or licensees in foreign countries which may not guarantee the same level of protection of personal information (“Third-Party Websites”). Links provided to Third-Party Websites on the Site are provided to you only as a convenience, and the inclusion of any link does not imply reliability or endorsement by us of the content of any such Third-Party Websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of Third-Party Websites, which may collect and use information from you in a manner different than how we do so; accordingly, once you leave the Wolverine platform, the use of such Third-Party Websites is entirely at your own risk. For relevant information, you should review the privacy statements or policies of any Third-Party Websites before using them. Other parties may collect information about your online activities over time and across different websites when you use our Site or services.

**_Children_**   
We do not intend to or knowingly collect identifiable personal information from children who are under 13 years of age. If you are a parent who believes that we have collected information about a child under age 13, please contact us using the contact information provided below with your child's name and address, and we will delete the information we have about your child from our records and provide confirmation in accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.

**_Transfer of Data to Other Countries_**   

Any information you provide to Wolverine through the use of the Site may be stored, processed, transferred among, and accessed from the United States and other countries which may not guarantee the same level of protection of personal information as the country in which you reside. However, Wolverine will handle your personal information in accordance with this Policy regardless of where your personal information is kept.

**_Notice to California Residents_**   

Under California law, California residents may request a list of all third parties to whom we have disclosed certain personal information (as defined by California law) during the preceding year for those third parties’ direct marketing purposes. If you are a California resident and would like to receive such a list, please contact us at the address listed in the “Accessing Personal Information” section below. For any such request, include the statement “Your California Privacy Rights” in the body of your request, as well as your name, street address, city, state, and zip code. Please provide enough information for us to determine if this applies to you. You must also attest to the fact that you are a California resident and provide a current California address for our response. Please note that we will not accept requests via the telephone, email, or by facsimile, and we are not responsible for notices that are not labeled or sent properly or that do not have complete information.

**_Notice to European Users_**   

The General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”) went into effect on May 25, 2018, and it is intended to protect personal information (as defined by GDPR) of European Union citizens. We do not actively market this Site to the European Union or its citizens in any meaningful way. However, if the personal information that you provide to us while using this Site, or while purchasing products or services from us is governed by GDPR, we will comply with all relevant provisions of the regulation. If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), or are accessing this Site from within the EEA, you have certain rights under GDPR - to exercise any of these rights, please contact us at: [DataProtectionOfficer@wwwinc.com.](mailto:DataProtectionOfficer@wwwinc.com)

**_Updates to Our Privacy Policy_**   

From time to time, we may post updates to this Policy. Any changes will be effective upon the posting of the revised Policy. We may also make, without notice, minor changes to the Policy that will not significantly affect our use of personal information. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices. This Policy was updated as of the effective date listed above. 

**_Contact Us_**   

If you have questions or concerns about our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at: 

> Wolverine World Wide, Inc.  
>  Attn: Director of Information Technology Security  
>  9341 Courtland Dr. NE  
>  Rockford, MI 49351  
>  Email: [ConsumerPrivacy@wwwinc.com](mailto:ConsumerPrivacy@wwwinc.com)
